{
  "reference_number": "13025",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": "flow gases such as methane are essentially in a carbon cycle, where methane emitted by animals breaks down on average in roughly\n 12years to carbon dioxide which is then sequestered by growing plants namely forages in photosynthesis so the carbon from CO2\n becomes carbohydrates and protein in the plants which is in turn eaten by animals and turned into meat, fibre or milk and some of\n\n the carbon forms methane and the cycle starts all over again. The first option is probably the best option to make the most impact on\n global warming from a New Zealand point of view. The second option could work as long as total carbon cycle was taken into account\n\n for the short lived gases and scientific study could come up with a true net warming effect if indeed there is one once the\n photosynthesis effect of forage plants sequestering CO2 is taken into account"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": "The best long term result is to come up with innovations and strategies to not emit CO2 such as electric vehicles, nuclear power,\n\n solar power"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "Conditions and especially science changes. Innovations and new knowledge will occur and policy has to be able to change to take\n advantage of this"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "as above"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Responses and Policy formation needs to be science led based on the best knowledge available globally. Please don't just consider\n\none side of the various carbon cycles that have CO2 as part of them. Emissions of GHG are one thing but the sequestering of carbon\nby all living plants not just trees is another side to the cycle especially for methane which needs to factored in to any GHG/Climate\n\nchange policy responses"
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "A qualified yes. First and foremost an understanding of the science is needed and the ability to test and understand whether policy\nproposals are based on the best knowledge available not pseudo-science"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "However it sounds like including adaption in the Bill will just create a new layer of bureaucracy and increases costs of compliance\n\nwithout actually achieving much. If it is going to cover adaption it should be for government funding of innovation and science to\ngenerate adaptive and resilience technologies such as drought resistant forages, or better building materials made from natural\n\nfibres such as wood."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "This is wishy-washy could mean anything stuff. The Government should keep it simple: fund science & R&D work both at\nCRI/University level and by the private sector to generate adaptive/resilience technologies and publicise/commercialise the useful\n\noutcomes well."
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "If this all ends up as badly run in terms of consistency across the country in terms of interpretation as the RMA this sort of policy will\nbe a waste of time. Please don't get carried away with policy for the sake of policy. Some responses will require Government\nintervention such as science funding but other responses such as housing close to the sea should be left to the market. Insurers will\n\nbe far better than the local or central government in assessing risk and some buildings will become un-insurable and could well lose\nvalue."
    }
  ]
}
